Hey y'all it's time for another edition of what would your ancestors say which I started last
night and um and it went so so well that I said um I need to keep doing this and um
so this is a part of a series that is attached to my one woman show what would the ancestors say
which I will be releasing the script of um and doing the new live stream show
um on November 8th and so keep it you know subscribe to my newsletter uh you know stay
tuned the link is coming soon so you guys can buy digital tickets the tickets will be $15 to watch
it digitally um and uh my book will be I got the masks all over the world uh and the book what
would the ancestors say which I am self-publishing will be available to also um purchase and again
support um my work so tonight who wants to join me to talk about what would their ancestors say
what would your ancestors say about where we are who are your ancestors um where would your ancestors
uh where your ancestors come from where would your ancestors frame the world that we're in right
now so for those of you who want to come on and talk you can request to come on please know that if
you request there is a good chance that I will bring you on screen so do not have do not be surprised
if I select you okay um if you don't know your ancestors then you need to get in touch with your
ancestors I think sometimes people feel like the concept of ancestors is like knowing the names of
the people you came from and the real truth is your ancestors are those who guide you right because
there's there's energy that comes off of humans that exists long after their bodies have left this
earth so your ancestors are those who connect to your energy and whose energy you connect to
so again it's not always just the literal concept of oh my ancestors came from this place it is also
the metaphysical concept of your ancestors that guide you and that you are a continuance of
because I will tell you you're going to be someone's ancestor so my show what would the ancestors say
this is the script and it's going to be published in a nice pretty book the the the ancestors what would
the ancestors say asks us that right asks us what would our ancestors say about where we are and
what kind of ancestors are we going to be so let's see who has requested to come on you you requested to
come on because what always happens is people request and then you bring them on and you like they like huh
who what okay so Cindy is not coming on let's see somebody else
uh so I don't know if Instagram is just not letting me bring people on
because I've now accepted two people let's try somebody else
I think it's just being stank because it's not letting this person join let's see somebody else
let's see if we're going to be able to bring anybody on
ah of course hello Amanda hi again how's it going
hi again hi again yeah this is our second time together
on your uh on your live when was the first time
oh it was uh I would say about a month and a bit ago
about a month ago month and a bit ago what were we talking about
well we were talking about Zionism and uh Kamala Harris yeah and how the two just go perfectly
together they do don't they and you know you know and I said to myself how can I prove that
Icarus flew so close to the sun right because Icarus was black that you know uses black as tar and
then how do I prove that and that Spellman wanted me to just just just come on your live and just to
prove it yeah Bellman wanted you oh you were the one who came on here to say that Kamala Harris was God
uh you know I mean I wouldn't say that she's she's God but you know
I think if I recall you were the one who came on here and you're the way that you were displaying your
point was very cryptic and for some reason you all think that I have the time to figure out your cryptic messaging
but I do not no because listen I mean I would listen if you do not I am a literal and direct
person and that is how I want to be spoken to and I love it I love it you know what and I'm a fan
listen black girls come on come on come on you're come on I'm a I'm a baby I'm we are not peers okay
no no you're not peers I am probably 20 years older than you are you sure about that I said
probably so no I'm not sure about that okay okay but you're probably time so are you going to speak
about your ancestors or absolutely yeah yeah no no certainly I am a right I am a dentist I'm also a
activist well and you know being the whitest of the whitest of the whitest of the blackest
you know I just have to say I totally I totally understand you I totally understand you I totally
understand you this woman is annoying yeah that's an annoying person
I love when y'all be with me y'all are like cut it out what what's happening
all y'all was like what's happening um moving on
hello hello turn the light on how are you doing this evening I am you in the whip I am in the whip
all right absolutely I figure I put a little light on the situation thank you I'm new to you I'm new
to your ecosystem and I've been impressed with what I've been hearing it's a breath of fresh air
and uh I want to before I answer your question I'd like to ask you a question for those of us that
we think we know who our ancestors are how do we reconnect to them and figure out who's really
kind of connecting with us you mean on a metaphysical level yes on a metaphysical level
I mean for me it really is one you being in nature and stillness
and learning how to turn off your consciousness and just be in receptor mode
and that requires removal of your ego which is really hard for all of us right because an ego is
not necessarily a bad thing all the time right like we need a certain amount of ego to just move
through the world but being able to shut off your judgment of you is as a big part of the ego right
like being able to receive whatever is told to you and not judge it and not argue with it
right so for me um and you have to be willing to talk to yourself
I see I see I see um so to your initial question ancestor wise or so I did my DNA on my mom's side
Cameroon dad's side Portugal and I think they're telling me now is to head back home to the continent
and reimagine life what it's like to be back there because I feel like here in the U.S. and I'm
out of Atlanta the signs are out there and then at this point it's just making a quality decision
to reimagine it back you know back home at least for me and and I guess at this point I just need to
navigate whether it's going to be back in in the area of Cameroon or on my dad's side or where my
wife's side is so we're kind of you know rethinking through what that's going to look like but that's
what I feel like for us is hey this place is you know is uh on the way to another side of things
that let's kind of reimagine what it's like to be back in Africa you know I feel like so many of us
are getting that specific messaging which is different to me than um get the fuck out of here
that's a which is legit messaging too right like some people are just like I feel like I gotta get out
of here but there's also something very um direct in feeling like no I gotta go to this specific place
to reconnect with this specific part of my soul that I've kind of had like that I haven't been able
to connect to here right and you know we've um so like two days ago was orange shirt day which honors the
um the the first nation tribe children in Canada who were taken from their homes and basically they
like beat the Indian out of them they're trying to kill the Indian in them right and I think for a lot of
us particularly black Americans we don't really acknowledge how after the civil rights movement um and you know we
were given more access into desegregated spaces there was a lot of that that was taken out of us
even out like we know that with slavery but we we forget that there was a whole lot of like our
black American indigeneity that was taken out of us right and so I think there's a whole reconnecting
process that does have to happen and I don't know that it has to be permanent you know like I don't know
that it necessarily has to be like uh okay I'm moving but you know in the aborigines the aboriginals
in um Australia they have a a spiritual um a spiritual what's the word I'm looking for
ritual called a walkabout and it's typically it's typically applied do you know what the walkabout is
that I want to explain to you if you already know I don't no I don't okay so it's a rite of passage
that young men do um where they basically gotta walk about they they walk out of the village and
they have to be out there for a certain amount of time and they gotta like figure it out
and during this time there's often you know peril but there's also you know solitude and the the space
to have you know isolated conversations by yourself without the disruption of your village
um and you know they be hallucinating like it's a time it's a time oh wow and I think so many of us
are being called to have our own version of a walkout even though we are not at like rite of passage age
you know even as as we're in our 40s and 50s I feel like there's a whole transitioning time that we are
having to take hold of and I think it's because we really have to transition into the the ancestors
that that shaped us you know when we have asada passing on that's like a that's a big one right
like that's that's a big one and it says to me like there are spaces on the path that have to be
filled in order to keep these spirits of of change and resistance moving on this path and like I don't
know that we're all equipped enough and look on that on that note I'd like to get your opinion on
something reincarnation do you feel like a lot of our do you feel like a lot of us are maybe in several
uh several lives now I'm on at least life number five oh really okay okay gotcha gotcha
I feel like I'm I've been I know I've been here before so I mean I just be feeling like
um there's though there's there's so there's those of us who just have a seeing eye
that feels familiar right like it's not even like oh I'm able to discern this it's like no I've seen
this before why did I see this it wasn't because of a PBS documentary like I feel this in my bones
you know I felt that since I was a child I feel like when I arrived here I was seven
and I was just like can we hurry up so I can get to adulthood and do what I'm supposed to do um
so I I I agree with you and you know so and that that kind of has me rethinking about how we look at
when our family or ancestors transition because you know energy is not void it continues it just moves
to another dimension and it's like we we kind of almost like we have to rethink about yes when
people transition and then doing that then that's going to give us a different view and we don't feel
this yeah we're going to miss them in the physical of course but learning how to reconnect with them
in the in the in the in the spirit realm yes and continue to act and and communicate with them as
if they're here because they're still it's still present which I'm starting to really really do
believe that reincarnation is a legitimate thing and then that just kind of helps you know peace peace
helps us put pieces of the puzzle together which is why I'm starting to think for a lot of us going
back to our homeland and I'm on it now speaking from an african-american standpoint this is going
to help us reconnect a lot of the dots which will help us heal yes learn who really are and we're not
kind of playing the you know the russian roulette of living through the lives of our colon you know
colonizers yes you know and and just have that you know that different frame of thinking so
I come with you you know the the indigenous peoples many indigenous peoples believe in reincarnation
and they also believe in um I think it's called the seven generations and they they do may make
decisions about how they function in their nations considering seven generations behind them and seven
generations forward right and that type of consciousness is another expansion of
community because it it leaves us uh it leads us into thinking beyond just like our mortality like
I feel like so much of what people don't understand about the United States and what's happening is
because they can only think within the time frame of their consciousness for some people that's as short
as the last two years that's why you have people saying things like oh they voted for this or oh imagine
if and it's like this was this has been in motion for so long the last two years was not the beginning of
this by any means by any means it would have taken somewhat of a revolution for it to stop in the last
two years like it wasn't just going to stop because of a vote so you know but there's a kind of business
that the native peoples and the first nations have that is outside of themselves that I think also
brings a peacefulness to like you said like lives passing on right and even in the healing that you're
talking about um I think that's that would shift also how we respond to loss and how we carry like
what our body does when we when we experience loss right and the the generational trauma that
lives in ourselves that we pass forward so you know I mean right let's also remember it's you know
everything most of what we've been taught has been taught to us for the purpose of control or capitalism
so I'm sure if I did some research on when death started being looked at like this it would have
something to do with trying to rule over us or get money from us because let me tell you these funeral
holes be homes be cashing in okay yeah listen these coffins is not cheap why are we buying why are we
bringing people in the lives you know that's a good question I mean I I like the idea now I'm okay
I'm fine with capitalism uh just when it gets to the higher level exploitation oh you got some
learning to do my brother you know what I'm saying you can't be fine with capitalism well I think I think
it can be healthy if it's if it can't be misused it cannot be healthy tell me what's your thoughts on
that capitalism cannot be healthy because capitalism exists only to capitalize on itself so there's no limit
it it continues to eat itself it literally exists in the same cellular framework as cancer there is
nothing that stops it the version that you think is healthy is socialism is what it's what socialism
okay so all right so let me uh let me re-pivot this back to your product your product that you're
selling okay now I'm assuming I'm gonna make an assumption that it's art okay so uh intellectual
um uh things that you created are you selling it for profit is that how would you how would you look
at it from what you developed capitalism is about exploitation and about scarcity okay all right I agree
there's there's there's still merchant hood right like there's still exchange exchange of goods
is still a very real thing it's just that in the society that we currently live in we exchange of goods
with money but to be quite honest I also exchange I barter with people right like so sometimes it's like
okay I'll come and do my show here if y'all uh do this thing for me um and that's a barter that's not a
transaction in the same way as money and what capitalism does is capitalism says okay I have to
praise I have to um place a price on something in order for it to be valuable and that is and that is
not true right so water is valuable without putting a price on it but what the price does is it creates a
scarcity and it says now I control this because by putting a price on it I determine who has access
to it so for my show what would the ancestors say I have been doing only free shows because I have been
creating this project from my soul and in exchange with the community and I have been doing only free
shows now at my shows I sell artwork right and all of my artwork is to uplift to empower to educate
so even if someone is giving me a form of currency they're getting a product that is valuable to them
beyond simply just consumerism which is something we do all the time okay so on that point and I agree
with everything you're saying and thank you for the re-education for that um with the with the artwork
are you putting a price on the artwork or is it what they see what they're offering you for it
no I believe that artists should be able to name their price for their work period whether you want
to pay for it or not is up to you and that's the difference now I'm creating intellectual property
I'm not taking water from the earth and then determining the something you need something you need
and then putting a price on it I'm not at a hospital with a skill set to save you and then saying you can't
get this unless you got that I'm simply providing you with my gifts and giving you the option
to pursue to partake in it or not so okay let me let me spin this around if I came up with this
amazing service or subscription-based service that I feel will help people save money in a particular
you know uh situation and if I say hey I'm not going to charge you for it but I'm going to let you
decide what you want to pay for it on a monthly basis how would that fit your terminology of
but yeah I mean it's like Radiohead Radiohead when they dropped in rainbows they said you can pay
whatever you want they said pay whatever you want but the the thing about it is that
a lot of times people can talk about capitalism but they can't talk about socialism do you know what
socialism is I do I do I like to hear how would you define socialism well I would define socialism as
rights that everyone has access to and that it's like a communal way of us contributing toward those
benefits or services so would you say that we have certain social policies socialism socialism policies
here in the United States I would so like social security all of our elected officials
in the in congress exist in socialism because we as a people are funding their health care
okay yeah we're we're funding their health care right now socialism simply says that there are
there's basically communal responsibility to the wellness of the community communism communism says
the community owns everything that runs the community so communism says
no one has individual ownership of that which runs the community um and you know a lot of people are
against communism because they've never seen it actually operating in the way that it idea ideologically
is supposed to exist and our ancestors really operated in many ways in socialist socialist dick societies
where those who had more were expected to do more and they were happy to do more because
if everybody's good then nobody is hurting and if people aren't hurting then it's less about less possibility
for them to hurt each other right so these are the things but but this this world of capitalism
keeps us in the chokehold that if everybody's good then nobody can be the best okay and and on that point
and I love that because that explains why why I feel like my ancestors are saying hey go experience what
it's like back in Africa so now you can get the closeness of what we what we intended for us to live like
and the communal you know feelings that come with that as you describe so now that you know has me thinking
in context what what biblical you know uh book or you know uh helps us understand what those true intentions
were like whatever you call it it's not a biblical book yeah i mean it ain't a bible um
right so whatever that is as it is but i mean really it's not necessarily a biblical book um
you know there's indigenous cultures all over the world that still operate in this sense in this way
and then there's like people like myself that operate in this way however you must understand that when you go back to
Africa Africa was also colonized and so except for Ethiopia so capitalism unfortunately has ravaged the
continent right and has made it a lot more difficult for folks to operate on a social level when you see
folks in the sahel like uh countries like niger burkina faso mali they are trying to not only apply
socialist mindsets into their nations but also the goal is to spread it across Africa in a pan-africanist
mindset so i'd like you for one more question then i'm going to bring somebody else okay okay all right
sorry about that thought of taking up everyone else's time um so two thoughts i'm hearing a no shortage and
lack is a condition that was created for for people to to experience yes we have an option to
deal with it or not two living by the spiritual laws versus you know quote-unquote man-made laws of
scarcity and such probably puts us more in alignment with what our ancestors have discovered now being
where they are and kind of being true to ourselves here so living more from a spiritual understand how
spiritual laws work versus the laws that are kind of with within us is that is that kind of the
foundation of where we are yes okay and that and that that is you just nailed it understanding the
spiritual laws that exist outside of the institutions because the institutions have wanted us to be
disconnected from those spiritual laws so that they could rule us with their laws which have nothing to do
with our wellness understood so you have a great night in atlanta shawty and hey look stay amazing
okay thanks for everything that's what's up have a good night brother oh what's your um what's your name
so i can tag you sure my name is joseph smith no your um your instagram name oh fan o maniac the number
one brand for the fan i am now a phantom maniac of yours all right phantom maniac yes all right thank
you brother have a good evening all right you too stay amazing now sometimes y'all is just being rude
like there's a difference between people who be on here being contrarian and people who be on here
like trying to get there and i know the difference i can feel the difference when someone is trying to get
there because they don't ask questions from a place of arrogance they ask questions from a place of
curiosity and that really is the biggest difference when you're interacting with somebody you have to
understand we have all been here if we're in this united states we've all been here indoctrinated this
whole time unless we had the real real real fortunate opportunity to like be raised in like pan-africanist
schools etc etc etc etc we have been indoctrinated so you know there is something there is a path and
a process that people have to go through and um i mean i mean some of y'all were getting frustrated but
i wasn't getting frustrated because i could tell that this was a brother that is curious you know and
curiosity is really like the best sign of compassion and and um connection that i feel that we can
exhibit so we are here at what would your ancestors say which is a live series that i'm doing here
um to converse with you guys about your ancestry um literal or figurative about how you are looking at
your ancestry how you're looking at yourself as an ancestor how you're preparing yourself for that
i'm also curious to know what do you feel like your ancestors would say about where we are in this
life in this world right now etc um so i want to remind you all that my show what would the ancestors
say my one woman show has i have taken the task of writing it down and memorializing it for you all to
be able to live with and learn with and love with and it will be released i'm self-publishing it it will
be released november 8th along with a live stream show that you'll be able to uh witness and you know
for those of you who all have been with me on this journey i started writing this show after i had to
cancel my tour because the zionists were getting my shows canceled and hacking my ticket site and it it you
you know i am i am thankful for being so connected to my ancestors because it's allowed me to have
resilience in the face of such wickedness right it's allowed me to have the the uh flexibility
to pivot right to pivot um in the face of such um tyranny and i pivoted straight to my ancestors and
started working on this piece that is now ready to be put in text and put in front of the people
and uh the rania effect phone in hand gat in the other this image harriet tubman on the phone with
her pistol is to remind you that your ancestors are always available to you on the main line armed and
ready to so there's a whole series of these that i'm doing and uh later this month i will
be releasing the malcolm x pin which i think you all are going to really appreciate so let's go to our
next person who uh wants to come up and talk about their ancestry all right thank you dm baby 38 so
while we're waiting remember that you can subscribe to my patreon and support my work there as well it's
five dollars a month um and you can be a member of the seal squad we have some seal squad members in
here right now so shout out i see miss debbie in here um and the seal squad is a really dope community
where we have done um just a really great job of protecting the space and making sure that folks
are coming in there to uplift to inform and to um empower each other so the person i added didn't it
didn't come through so let's go to this person and see if it will work for them to come up hold
on let me get my food before these raccoons get it hold on one second i didn't answer she's just going
she'll be right here because the raccoons will come and get my food hello hi we just want to let you
know that our ancestor would be so proud that all i am white from posto so it's impossible
i live in chicago though because i came here as a refugee when the war when the war hit so our love
my love for america was very platonic and very oh my god the first boyfriend that just lies to you
and then um once i gave birth i kind of just got disappointed
once i had adulthood it was just a disappointment i'm not here to i'm not here to steal your time i'm
here you're not stealing time no no this you're not stealing time for everyone this is for everyone
this is not just for people with black ancestors this is for everyone i want to hear about you
know your ancestry and and what you think about them and what they think about what you think they
think about now i mean you made it you you came to the united states to escape um so you are bosnian or
serbian no i'm from i'm albanian are you sure okay okay yes i am so i'm albanian from kosovo we we were
it was yugoslavia so we were under yes okay we were under uh a serbian and it was a genocide in bosnia
for a long time and then eventually i guess america was like let's not make a mess there in kosovo as
well as in basia so then they kind of decided to save us um but that's how i came as as refugee i was
sent to a new york bronx so my all my teachers all my doctors and everything uh were black people so my
my my my safeness and when when talking to people is always even when i go to the doctors
here in lury children's hospital or my uh northwestern i say please a black doctor because i'm sweating
right because that was your entrance into the states fascinating i i i guess that's the the
the welcomeness and it was very different nonetheless i'm shaking my son is like you're shaking
no because you know americans we we we are so cut off from learning about other people other cultures
um and you know what what is so what is it like to be disrupted from you know the lineage of your your
home is it i don't think that they understand the magnitude of the disruption that they that they
give to uh any any population who they're trying to like push away for example now with palestine happening
i was not educated at all on what was going on but just the idea of seeing kids i reposted one of your
posts this is maybe two years ago and i was working for a company uh that i got sent to hr i got blocked
from a lot of people so that's when i understood i'm like oh this this is not funny right so i stopped
i i followed you all the time but i put in repost i'm like okay i need i need my paycheck i can't
i'm a single mom but the thing is that bugs me the most it's the people who has actually who have
actually witnessed some something like i did i was eight years old when the war happened i heard all
the bombs we were sleeping with like uh shoes on and like jackets on just in case something happens and we
can't be ready to freaking sleep yeah um people that go through war have this tendency uh on like
kind of dealing with it i guess better because they have this guilt on uh
i am inferior so i'm glad to be alive and they don't have it like oh what's happening to me and blah
blah blah blah they don't have that uh white american woman crocodile tears like we that's
that's not what happened so that bugs me the the most it's like do not minimize what we went through
like don't minimize it there's no need to minimize it and the other thing that bugs me the most that
that people that come from these places that you uh whatever the case is don't have the education
enough the tools to actually understand what's going on so the easiest way to kind of grab people is by
teaching them racist racism or capitalism so what bugs me the most is that i have
i have family members i have friends i have that are on the other side so that is what
irritates the shit out of me i want to say like how can you right i've been through the war
you've seen this shit you've seen what a genocide is still just because someone saved you they saved
you because they had they had a purpose to save you or because they wanted to save you
you but how can people how can people do that when they went to that so you all you know it's
interesting because that is on a bigger scale like what we're seeing with israel right it's like you
all are claiming judaism yeah exactly we all know the holocaust
and yet you're trying to out holocaust the holocaust it's mind-boggling yeah and i feel like my own
people in this country when i see um because what what you're also talking about is there's a certain
safety in assimilating um you know a lot of people feel like oh i just need to go along with like the the
the the masses and then they'll take care of me um which never happens by the way um because
the if the masses are not like the american culture is not about taking care of each other
like that's not the mindset so if you go along with it with them with like okay if dollar rate
they're racist so this is the easiest way to exist in america i guess i'll be racist too it's like
like they're gonna turn on you too they they turn on everybody precisely like i have so many
i have a family members that would be like well this doesn't affect me i said well it affects me
i'm on medicare because i have a nephrotic boy like it affects me it affects where uh my child goes to
school because we're in south loop in chicago and most of my uh uh kids friends are uh are black he
hangs out with them all the time i pick them up i drag them to school like it's affecting me so
yes the fear is what's stopping i want to say most of my people speaking out but then again it's this idea
even if they speak in kosovo they will kind of be um labeled as extremist of the uh uh a muslimic
sect or it's too too much like no we uh they're right they don't treat women well they're do you know
that that uh kind of just a a headline of some history that they use i'm like but they don't treat
women well here nor there like it's it's it's everywhere so do you think they're missing a a a a a
curtain that they need to open and do you think that only uh can be get in if they attend therapy
because i've been to i went to therapy and yeah i think that is kind of what opened a lot gave me tools
to kind of fish on a different way he does what therapy does and this is what you just
mentioned is therapy we carry the the we carry our ancestors in us like we carry their dna we carry
um you know their there's a really good book called my grandmother's hands by rest american that talks
about like intergenerational trauma and how like if you like your cells are affected by what yeah
experience and then you have a child and then those cells go into the child and so that cellular
structure starts to change when you actively do work to change it right and so that's what therapy
is so therapy allows you to heal the more you heal the less on edge you are the less um you know
defensive you are because the more solid you are in yourself and so many people are unable to take
in new ideas because it's going to like shake up their fragile foundations you know they're like built
on sand someone gave them their identity they don't have it themselves therapy like allows you to get your
own identity and then that's when you're able to really like see the world beyond yourself you know
yeah i think i think you saying that therapy allows you to get your own identity
identity is as well i'll be using to the rest of my family
well you have a great night thank you so much i'm so happy for this i need a screenshot this okay
thank you thank you he's a savage okay he's a savage
so unfortunately instagram is doing the thing where the comments aren't scrolling for me so
i have no idea what you guys are saying um but it's already 8 52 so we we've already had two
folks on tonight in the comments are scrolling so i'm gonna end it but we will be back tomorrow night
here to ask what would your ancestors say at 8 pm eastern so come on and hopefully you'll get a chance
to come on and share um i think it's really dope getting to have these conversations with y'all and
for you to be having those conversations by yourself even if you're not having them online
we have to be asking ourselves this question because it is really imperative that we break
out of the habit of only thinking within our like limited time frame we only think in the now and then
when shit pop off we'd be like how'd this happen it's like well it was actually happening but she was
only thinking in the now and i know that there is something to be said for being present right
and i'm not saying that we forget to smell the roses and to look at the bees no we do that while
also being cognizant of the fact that by stopping to smell the roses by protecting the bees we are still
allowing for there to be more around us to flourish right we have a consciousness about what that does
and i think there's just a a really important piece of of work and process that all of us have
to really adhere to and continue to do and i'm happy to be doing it right here with you guys so
mark your calendars november 8th my book what would the ancestors say is released as well as the live
stream show i hope that you guys will support and show you love the uh the price for the live stream show
is 15 zalas and um man we're gonna keep on going i'll see y'all tomorrow night and uh shout out to
all of my folks in chicago i know things are getting really heated up there and this man is really on one
and it's gonna take us staying um staying clear-headed and in community
to if we have any shot at being a true oppositional force